<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./file_system_connector.png"
	type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">

    <name>Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2 Connector</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Connects to Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2 (ADLS Gen2) in order to read/write files in downstream nodes.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>This node connects to Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2 (ADLS Gen2). The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access
            the ADLS Gen2 data as a file system, e.g. to read or write files and folders,
            or to perform other file system operations (browse/list files, copy, move, ...).
            </p>
            
            <p>This node requires the <i>Microsoft Authenticator</i> to perform authentication.</p>
            
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths for ADLS Gen2 are specified with a UNIX-like syntax, for example
            <tt>/mycontainer/myfolder/myfile</tt>, which is an absolute path that consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash (<tt>/</tt>).</li>
                    <li>The name of a container (<tt>mycontainer</tt>), followed by a slash.</li>
                    <li>The name of a folder (<tt>myfolder</tt>), followed by a slash.</li>
                    <li>Followed by the name of a file (<tt>file.csv</tt>).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
	        <option name="Working directory">
	            Specifies the <i>working directory</i> using the path syntax explained above. The working directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream
	            nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i> paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. If not specified, the default working directory
	            is <tt>/</tt>.
	        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
        	<option name="Service calls timeout">
        		The time in seconds allowed between sending a request and receiving the response.
        	</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Credential">
    		Attach the Microsoft Authenticator node to perform authentication and provide
    		a credential. 
    	</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2 File System Connection">
             Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2 File System Connection
        </outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
