<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./file_system_connector.png"
	type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">

    <name>Azure Blob Storage Connector</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Connects to Azure Blob Storage in order to read/write files in downstream nodes.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>This node connects to Azure Blob Storage. The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access
            the Azure Blob Storage data as a file system, e.g. to read or write files and folders,
            or to perform other file system operations (browse/list files, copy, move, ...).
            </p>
            
            <p>This node requires the <i>Microsoft Authentication</i> to perform authentication. The following authentication modes are supported:
            <ul>
            <li>Interactive Authentication</li>
            <li>Username/password Authentication</li>
            <li>Shared key authentication (Azure Storage only)</li>
            <li>Shared access signature (SAS) authentication (Azure Storage only)</li>
            </ul>
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths for Azure Blob Storage are specified with a UNIX-like syntax, <tt>/mycontainer/myfolder/myfile</tt>. An absolute
            for Azure Blob Storage consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash (<tt>/</tt>).</li>
                    <li>Followed by the name of a container (<tt>mycontainer</tt> in the above example), followed by a slash.</li>
                    <li>Followed by the name of an object within the container (<tt>myfolder/myfile</tt> in the above example).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
	        <option name="Working directory">
	            Specifies the <i>working directory</i> using the path syntax explained above. The working directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream
	            nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i> paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. If not specified, the default working directory
	            is <tt>/</tt>.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Normalize paths">
	            Determines if the path normalization should be applied. Path normalization eliminates redundant components of a path like, e.g. <tt>/a/../b/./c</tt> can be normalized to <tt>/b/c</tt>.
	            When these redundant components like <tt>../</tt> or <tt>.</tt> are part of an existing object, then normalization must be deactivated in order to access them properly.
	        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
        	<option name="Service calls timeout">
        		The time allowed between sending a request and receiving the response.
        	</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Microsoft Connection">
    		Microsoft Connection that provides user authentication.
    	</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Azure Blob Storage File System Connection">
            Azure Blob Storage File System Connection
        </outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
