<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode 
	icon="./azurebsconnection16x16.png" type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Azure Blob Store Connection (legacy)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Configures the connection information used to
        connect to Azure Blob Store.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	<p>
        		This node configures the connection information that will be used to connect to the Azure Blob Store (AzureBS). Using this 
        		connection, the other KNIME remote file handling nodes can be used to create directory, list, delete, 
        		download and upload files from and to AzureBS. 
        	</p>
        	<p>
        		The connection information is encoded in the format <i>azurebs://storageAccount@blob.core.windows.net</i>. The protocol is 
        		<i>azurebs</i>. The first folder path is the container name and the rest is the 
        		blob name, e.g. <i>azurebs://knimeaccount@blob.core.windows.net/knimecontainer/data/iris.data</i> defines the object 
        		<i>data/iris.data</i> in the container <i>knimecontainer</i>. 
        		The storage account is <i>knimeaccount</i>.
        	</p>        	
        	<p>
        		The container name and the blob name are needed in order to delete, download, or upload objects 
        		from a list. The storage account is not needed. For instance, to delete the above mentioned object <i>iris.data</i>,
        		it is necessary to encode the path to <i>azurebs://knime-bucket/data/iris.data</i> in the list.        		
        	</p>
			<p>
				<i>This legacy file handling node has been replaced by the
				</i><a href="https://kni.me/n/1iu8u7meRrzU-iPg"><i>Azure Blob Storage Connector</i></a><i>
				and will be deprecated in the foreseeable future. For further information about the 
				new file handling framework see the
				</i><a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html"><i>File Handling Guide.
				</i></a><br/>
			</p>
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Workflow Credentials">
        	Use workflow credentials to determine the storage account and the access key. 
        	The login is used as the storage account and the password is used as the access key.
        </option>
        <option name="Storage Account">
        	The AzureBS storage account used to authenticate.
        </option>
        <option name="Access Key">
        	The AzureBS access key used to authenticate.
        </option>
        <option name="Timeout">
        	The timeout in milliseconds when initially establishing a connection.
        </option>
        <option name="Test connection">
        	Open dialog that tests the current connection.
        </option>
               
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>        
        <outPort index="0" name="Connection information port">
        	Port object containing the AzureBS connection information.
        </outPort>        
    </ports>        
</knimeNode>
